[
    {
      "question": "The first generation computer could be?",
      "options": [
        "Networking",
        "Batch Processing",
        "Miti-tabulation",
        "Multi-tasking"
      ],
      "answer": "Batch Processing"
    },
    {
      "question": "A desktop computer is also known as?",
      "options": [
        "Laptop", 
        "Mainframe", 
        "Palmtop",
        "PC"
        ],
      "answer": "PC"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is generally costlier?",
      "options": [
        "Mainframe", 
        "Personal computer",
        "Notebook computer",
        "Server"
        ],
      "answer": "Mainframe"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following can be consider as portable computer?",
      "options": [
        "Desktop", 
        "PDA", 
        "Mainframe computer", 
        "Mini computer"
      ],
      "answer": "PDA"
    },
    {
      "question": "Modem is a?",
      "options": [
        "Word processing software", 
        "Application software", 
        "Hardware", 
        "Liveware"
      ],
      "answer": "Hardware"
    },
    {
      "question": "Name the application used for creating presentations?",
      "options": [
        "MS Access",
        "MS Word",
        "MS Excel",
        "MS PowerPoint"
      ],
      "answer": "MS PowerPoint"
    },
    {
      "question": "Shell is the exclusive feature of?",
      "options": [
        "Application software", 
        "System software", 
        "DOS", 
        "UNIX"
      ],
      "answer": "UNIX"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which was the computer conceived by babbage?",
      "options": [
        "Donald knuth", 
        "Arithmetic machine", 
        "Analytical engine", 
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Arithmetic machine"
    },
    {
      "question": "The combination of operating system and processor in a computer is referred to as computer?",
      "options": [
        "Minimum requirements", 
        "Specifications", 
        "Platform", 
        "Firmware"
      ],
      "answer": "Platform"
    },
    {
      "question": "Programs stored inROM are called as?",
      "options": [
        "Fireware", 
        "Formware", 
        "Farmware", 
        "Firmware"
      ],
      "answer": "Farmware"
    },
    {
      "question": "UNIVAC is?",
      "options": [
        "Universal Automatic Computer",
        "Universal Array Computer",
        "Unique Automatic Computer",
        "Unvalued Automatic Computer"
      ],
      "answer": "Universal Automatic Computer"
    },
    {
      "question": "The basic operations performed by a computer are?",
      "options": [
        "Arithmetic operations",
        "Logistic operations",
        "Storage and relative",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "The two major types of computer chips are?",
      "options": [
        "External memory chip", 
        "Primary memory chip", 
        "Microprocessor chip", 
        "Both b and c"
      ],
      "answer": "Both b and c"
    },
    {
      "question": "Computer is free from tiresome and boardoom. We call it?",
      "options": [
        "Accuracy", 
        "Reliability", 
        "Diligence", 
        "Versatility"
      ],
      "answer": "Diligence"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of computer uses the 8-bit code called EBCDIC?",
      "options": [
        "Minicomputers",
        "Microcomputers",
        "Mainframe computers",
        "Super computers"
      ],
      "answer": "Microcomputers"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following was a special purpose computer?",
      "options": [
        "ABC",
        "ENIAC",
        "EDVAC",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "ABC"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not processing?",
      "options": [
        "Arranging",
        "Manipulating",
        "Calculating",
        "Gathering"
      ],
      "answer": "Gathering"
    },
    {
      "question": "The digital computer was developed primarily in?",
      "options": [
        "USSR",
        "Japan",
        "USA",
        "UK"
      ],
      "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
      "question": "The arranging of data in a logical sequence is called ?",
      "options": [
        "Sorting",
        "Classifying",
        "Reporting",
        "Summarizing"
      ],
      "answer": "Sorting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Instructions and memory address are represented by?",
      "options": [
        "Character code",
        "Binary code",
        "Binary word",
        "Parity bit"
      ],
      "answer": "Binary code"
    }
  ]
  